Business Affairs, Office of; Records ua330
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of Business Affairs Records
1914-1978
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Business Office
ua330
1.37 cubic ft.
Contains budget and administrative planning records from the Business Office and the Office of the Dean for Administration, primarily dating from the mid- to late-1960s.
Access
Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
The Business Office, headed by the Director of Business Affairs, succeeded the position of Financial Secretary circa 1966. It was overseen by the Vice President of Management and Planning and existed until the organizational structure was changed and the Division of Finance and Business was created in 1977
Scope and Contents
This collection contains budget reports and financial planning materials, pertaining to various aspects of running the campus. This includes acquisition of materials for departments as well as coordination of the telephone system and payment of bills on campus. Many of these docuemnts were memos sent out to all faculty and staff informing them of imminent changes to University protocol.
The collection also contains administrative records associated with Elmer C. Mathews, the Dean of Administration (later referred to as Dean of Personnel Administration).
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized in the way it was recieved, maintaining the original order. Folders in poor condition have been replaced, maintaining the original folder titles.
Education, Higher--Administration; Budget process; Budget; Administrative records; Financial Records; UAlbany Finance & Business; State University of New York at Albany
- Business Affairs, 1975 April-1978 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Data Processing Notes - Pamphlets (Computer), 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Energy Consumption Data, 1972 December-1973 October (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Administration Manual for Overseas Program Directors, 1970 September (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Proposal for Newly Revised Administrative Data Proccessing System for SUNY Albany, 1965 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Business Office Affairs, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Budget Control and Reconiliation Data, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bell and Howeel Proposal and Information, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Student Assistants, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Bank Deposit books, 1923-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Budget Survey Report, 1949 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Middle State Accreditation, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous-Papers and Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Telephones (CENTREX), 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Summer, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Official Ovest Housing, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Grants, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Space Inventory, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Secretarial Workshops, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Request for Faculty Appointments, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Special Events: Summer, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Summer Special Programs, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Final Examination, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Budget Summer, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- ASSTS Summer, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Summer Notes and Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Faculty Summer, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Routined- Emergency Maintenance Service, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Employees Rating, 1953 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Facilities, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Grants, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Registration, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Administration Work, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Administrative Cabinet Memos, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Functions and Offices, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Nepotism Policy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- New Campus Tip Sheet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Business, General, 1966; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Telephone & Switchboard, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Student Assistant stipend tables & Payroll information, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Special Service Survey, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Library Book Binding, Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Safeguarding Essential Records, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Telephone Price Increase, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Tie Line Usage, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
- New Telephone Tie Line System, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Financial Bulletin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Purchasing and Budgets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
- SUNY Policies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Functions and Offices, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- University Rules and Regulations For Travel, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Huyck Preserve, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Loan Funds, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Repairs: Boys Locker Room, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- War Assets Administration, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Payrolls and Payroll Changes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Fees Collected, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Travel Expenses, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Maintenance and Services, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correction to Code Book, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Appropriations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Ashes and Cool-Bids, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Fees, Rules and Regulations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Employees Retirement, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Division of Budget, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Department of Civil Service, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Department of Audit and Control, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Department of Architecture, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Overtime Compensation, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Overtime Rates, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Repairs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Surplus Property, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)